{"name": "Z08  2022-4", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. On Monday, Elsa put $40 in her empty lockbox. Each following Monday, Elsa will deposit $18 to her lockbox. Which of the following expressions gives the number of dollars in Elsa's lockbox after Elsa's deposit w weeks from now?", "choices": {"A": "40 + 18w", "B": "40 - 18w", "C": "40w + 18", "D": "40w - 18", "E": "(40 + 18)w"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Raheem made a down payment of $250.00 at a local store for an HDTV that cost $880.00 with tax included. He arranged to make 8 equal monthly payments to the store to finish paying for the HDTV. Given that he paid no additional fees, how much was Raheem's monthly payment?", "choices": {"A": "$ 78.75", "B": "$ 80.00", "C": "$110.00", "D": "$140.00", "E": "$141.25"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. What is 25% of 50% of 80 ?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "10", "C": "20", "D": "40", "E": "60"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. In scientific notation, 0.00041 = ?", "choices": {"A": "4.1 \u00d7 10-5", "B": "4.1 \u00d7 10-4", "C": "4.1 x 10-3", "D": "4.1 \u00d7 103", "E": "4.1 x 104"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. What is the value of 5xy2 when x = -2 and y = -4 ?", "choices": {"A": "-320", "B": "-160", "C": "160", "D": "320", "E": "1,600"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. What is the value of | -8 | - | 7 - 33 | ?", "choices": {"A": "-34", "B": "-18", "C": "18", "D": "34", "E": "48"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Given that a3ak = a9 for all real numbers a, what is the value of k ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "6", "D": "12", "E": "27"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. What is the least common multiple of 20, 30, and 130 ?", "choices": {"A": "60", "B": "78", "C": "180", "D": "780", "E": "78,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. If f(x) = 2x2 + 6x - 7, then f(-3) = ?", "choices": {"A": "-37", "B": "-7", "C": "7", "D": "11", "E": "29"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. In the figure below,  and  intersect at point A. Points G and D are in the interiors of angles \u2220BAF and \u2220CAE, respectively. Some angle measures are given. What is the measure of \u2220BAG \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "56\u00b0", "B": "60\u00b0", "C": "84\u00b0", "D": "90\u00b0", "E": "96\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Salma attended a concert on Friday. She arrived at the concert hall at 5:46 p.m. and left the concert hall at 11:27 p.m. How long was Salma at the concert hall?", "choices": {"A": "5 hours 19 minutes", "B": "5 hours 41 minutes", "C": "6 hours 19 minutes", "D": "6 hours 21 minutes", "E": "6 hours 41 minutes"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Given that x \u2264 3 and x + y \u2265 5, what is the LEAST value that y can have?", "choices": {"A": "-8", "B": "-2", "C": "0", "D": "2", "E": "8"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. In the figure below, parallel lines l and m are intersected by transversal n, forming the numbered angles. Which of the following congruence statements is NOT necessarily true?", "choices": {"A": "\u22201 \u224c \u22205", "B": "\u22202 \u224c \u22208", "C": "\u22203 \u224c \u22205", "D": "\u22204 \u224c \u22207", "E": "\u22206 \u224c \u22208"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. What is the largest possible product for 2 even integers whose sum is 50 ?", "choices": {"A": "96", "B": "100", "C": "184", "D": "400", "E": "624"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. The blood types of 150 people are determined for a study. The results show that 62 people have Type O blood,  67 have Type A blood, 15 have Type B blood, and the others have Type AB blood. If 1 person from this study is randomly selected, what is the probability that this person has either Type O or Type AB blood?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. If x + y = 26 and r - y = 14, then y = ?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "7", "C": "12", "D": "20", "E": "40"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. The chart below shows the possible combinations of numbers that can land faceup when 2 numbered cubes are rolled at the same time. Each combination is equally likely.What is the probability of rolling the numbered cubes so that the sum of the numbers that land faceup is 8 or greater?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. The graph of the function  is shown in the standard (x.v) coordinate plane below. The function is defined for values of x strictly between which of the following pairs of numbers?", "choices": {"A": "-10 and -1", "B": "-1 and 0", "C": "0 and 1", "D": "1 and 10", "E": "  10 and 100"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. To increase the mean of 7 numbers by 3, by how much would the sum of the 7 numbers have to increase?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "7", "C": "10", "D": "21", "E": "42"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the line with equation y + 1 = (2x + 8) has a slope of:", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "2", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. A parallelogram has a perimeter of 88 inches, and 1 of its sides measures 18 inches. If it can be determined, what are the lengths, in inches, of the other 3 sides?", "choices": {"A": "18, 18, 34", "B": "18, 17, 17", "C": "18, 26, 26", "D": "18, 35, 35", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Five friends play golf at a course that charges both an annual membership fee and a fee to play each round. Each point on the scatterplot below represents the number of rounds each person played during a year and the total fees the golf course charged that person.", "choices": {"A": "$ 0.75", "B": "$ 30.00", "C": "$ 53.68", "D": "$ 90.00", "E": "$ 300.00"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Tom\u00e1s wants to tile a rectangular floor with square tiles that measure 12 inches on a side. The floor measures 10 feet 6 inches long by 8 feet 6 inches wide. If he is able to cut the tiles without waste, what is the minimum whole number of tiles Tom\u00e1s needs to completely cover the floor?", "choices": {"A": "80", "B": "90", "C": "98", "D": "99", "E": "100"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below, \u25b3ABC is bounded by AB, AC, and the y-axis. Which of the following values is closest to the area, in square coordinate units, of \u25b3ABC ?", "choices": {"A": "15.8", "B": "31.6", "C": "35.0", "D": "70.0", "E": "79.1"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. In right triangle \u25b3JKL, the right angle is at K, the length of JK is 10 cm, and sin L = .  What is the value of cos J ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. John averages 60 miles per hour (mph) the 6 hours he travels from his house to Ling's house. On his return trip, John experiences heavy traffic due to construction zones. He averages 36 mph the first 3 hours of his return trip. What is the average speed, in miles per hour, John must drive for the rest of the return trip for a return trip of 7 hours?", "choices": {"A": "42", "B": "48", "C": "54", "D": "63", "E": "66"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Use the following information to answer questions 27-29.At Western High School and Eastern High School, 200 students and 100 students, respectively, were surveyed to determine their fast-food preferences. Each of the 300 students indicated 1 preference among 5 choices, as summarized in the pie charts below.       (Note: Each pie chart is made up of sectors that are proportional in size to the percent of students they represent.)27.  How many students surveyed at Western High School indicated chicken as their preference?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "17", "C": "24", "D": "36", "E": "40"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Use the following information to answer questions 27-29.At Western High School and Eastern High School, 200 students and 100 students, respectively, were surveyed to determine their fast-food preferences. Each of the 300 students indicated 1 preference among 5 choices, as summarized in the pie charts below.       (Note: Each pie chart is made up of sectors that are proportional in size to the percent of students they represent.)28. What is the measure, to the nearest 1\u00b0, of the central angle of the sector that represents the number of students at Western High School who indicated pizza as their preference?", "choices": {"A": "40\u00b0", "B": "80\u00b0", "C": "108\u00b0", "D": "120\u00b0", "E": "144\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Use the following information to answer questions 27-29.At Western High School and Eastern High School, 200 students and 100 students, respectively, were surveyed to determine their fast-food preferences. Each of the 300 students indicated 1 preference among 5 choices, as summarized in the pie charts below.       (Note: Each pie chart is made up of sectors that are proportional in size to the percent of students they represent.)29. The same survey was taken at Central High School. The percent of students at Eastern High School who indicated chicken as their preference was 1 more than  the percent of students at Central High School who indicated chicken as their preference. What percent of students at Central High School indicated chicken as their preference?", "choices": {"A": "3%", "B": "4%", "C": "8%", "D": "9%", "E": "12%"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Jermaine will build a metal wall sculpture that is composed of 3 circles of different sizes, shown below. The smallest circle will have a diameter of 8 inches, and the diameters of the 3 circles will be in the ratio of 1:2:4. To reinforce the sculpture, Jermaine will place a straight metal bar from the center of the smallest circle, through the center of the middle circle, to the center of the largest circle. What will be the length, in inches, of the bar?", "choices": {"A": "28", "B": "36", "C": "56", "D": "64", "E": "72"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Juan will flip a fair 2-sided coin and spin a wheel. The coin has 1 heads side and 1 tails side. The wheel has an equal chance of stopping on any one of its 4 sections: red, blue, yellow, and green. What is the probability that the coin lands tails side up and the wheel stops on the green section?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. The volume of air, in liters, in the lungs of an average person during normal breathing is a function of time, in seconds. This function is modeled by the sine function graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. One of the following values is the period, in seconds, of this function. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "0.5", "B": "2.4", "C": "2.5", "D": "2.9", "E": "5.0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. If f(x) = 5x and g(x) = -2, then -f(g(x)) = ?", "choices": {"A": "-25", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. In the circle shown below, C is the center, AB is a diameter, and CD is a radius of length 10 inches that is perpendicular to AB. Which of the following values is closest to the area, in square inches, of the shaded region (the combined area of the semicircle and \u25b3BCD)?", "choices": {"A": "150", "B": "186", "C": "207", "D": "236", "E": "264"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. During one of their routines, the Longsboro High School marching band members line up in a succession of L-shaped formations. The first 4 formations, numbers 1 through 4, are shown below, with each dot representing a band member. The pattern demonstrated by the addition of band members in the first 4 formations continues through each successive L-shaped formation in the routine. Which of the following equations gives the relationship between n, the formation number, and b, the number of band members in that formation?", "choices": {"A": "b = n + 2", "B": "b = n + 4", "C": "b = 2n + 3", "D": "b = 3n + 2", "E": "b = 5n "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. The Better Cellular Company offers customers 2 monthly plans. Plan A costs $40.00 per month plus $0.05 per minute of time used, while Plan B costs $20.00 per month plus $0.10 per minute of time used. What is the least whole number of minutes a customer could use in 1 month to make Plan A less expensive than Plan B for that month?", "choices": {"A": "50", "B": "51", "C": "399", "D": "400", "E": "401"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "3x2", "B": "3x4", "C": "3x8", "D": "9x4", "E": "9x8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. A pyramid has a square base with a side length of 6 feet. The volume of the pyramid is 144 cubic feet. What is the height, in feet, of the pyramid?(Note: The volume of a pyramid with base area B and height h is Bh.)", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "12", "C": "24", "D": "48", "E": "72"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. What is the value of  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. What are all the real solutions to the equation | 1-2x | = 3 ?", "choices": {"A": "x = -1 only", "B": "x = -1 and x = -2", "C": "x = -1 and x = 1", "D": "x = -1 and x = 2", "E": "x = 1 and x = 2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. For what value of a would the following system of equations have an infinite number of solutions?                                          2x - 3y = 6                     4x - 6y = 3a", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "6", "D": "12", "E": "18"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. In the equation ax + b = 0, when a, x, and b are integers and x and b are positive, a must be:", "choices": {"A": "negative and a factor of b.", "B": "negative and a multiple of b.", "C": "positive and a factor of b.", "D": "positive and a multiple of b.", "E": "positive and equal to b."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Given the complex numbers 2 - i and 2 + i, which of the following expressions is equal to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Which of the following fractions is closest to 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. A spin of a certain spinner has 5 possible outcomes. The table below shows the probability of spinning each of the 5 outcomes. The probability of spinning Outcome 4 is a and the probability of spinning Outcome 5 is 2a. What is the value of a ?", "choices": {"A": "0.06", "B": "0.09", "C": "0.12", "D": "0.18", "E": "0.33"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. The quadrants of the standard (x,y) coordinate plane are shown below. The vertices of \u25b3ABC are A(-3,3), B(-3,1) and C(-1, 1). The triangle is translated by x' = x + 5 and y' = y - 2.  The image of (x,y) on \u25b3ABC is (x',y') on \u25b3A'B'C'. The vertices of \u25b3A'B'C' lie in which quadrant(s)?", "choices": {"A": "Quadrant I only", "B": "Quadrant Il only", "C": "Quadrant III only", "D": "Quadrants I and IV only", "E": "Quadrants II and III only"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. The figure below shows a map of Jennifer's neighborhood.Which of the following expressions represents the straight-line distance, in miles, from Jennifer's home to school?(Note: For a triangle with sides of length a, b, and c that are opposite angles \u2220A, \u2220B, and \u2220C respectively, , and c2 = a2 + b2 - 2ab cos \u2220C.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. The graph below shows the function f(x) =  in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. Which of thefollowing is an equation of the horizontal asymptote of f(x)?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.In the ellipse shown below, AC is the major axis with length 16 feet, BD is the minor axis with length 12 feet, and E is the center. Point F lies on side BC of the inscribed rhombus ABCD.49. For any ellipse, the area is \u03c0ab, where a and b are half the lengths of the major and minor axes, respectively. What is the area, in square feet, of the shaded region (the region outside the rhombus and inside the ellipse)?", "choices": {"A": "12\u03c0 - 24", "B": "12\u03c0 - 48", "C": "48\u03c0 - 48", "D": "48\u03c0 - 96", "E": "192\u03c0 - 96"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.In the ellipse shown below, AC is the major axis with length 16 feet, BD is the minor axis with length 12 feet, and E is the center. Point F lies on side BC of the inscribed rhombus ABCD.50.  Which of the following expressions gives the measure of \u2220EBC?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.In the ellipse shown below, AC is the major axis with length 16 feet, BD is the minor axis with length 12 feet, and E is the center. Point F lies on side BC of the inscribed rhombus ABCD.51. The eccentricity, e, of an ellipse is a measure of the flatness of the ellipse. The eccentricity of a circle is 0. The value of e is given by the ratio , where a and b are half the lengths of the major and minor axes, respectively. Which of the following intervals contains the value of e for this ellipse?", "choices": {"A": "0.0 &lt; e &lt; 0.2", "B": "0.2 &lt; e &lt; 0.4", "C": "0.4 &lt; e &lt; 0.6", "D": "0.6 &lt; e &lt; 0.8", "E": "0.8 &lt; e &lt; 1.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Given the recursive formula below, which of the following equations is a correct explicit formula for the sequence?                         a1 = 10                   an + 1 = 2an", "choices": {"A": "an = 8 + 2n", "B": "an = 9 + n", "C": "an = 9 + 2n", "D": "an = 10(2n)", "E": "an = 10(2n - 1)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. A toddler has 2 sets of blocks. The blocks within each set are equal-sized cubes. The blocks within one set are smaller than the blocks within the other set. The edge length of each smaller block is  the edge length of each larger block. How many of the smaller blocks must be stacked together to create an arrangement with the same volume as 1 larger block?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "6", "C": "4", "D": "3", "E": "2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. What is the determinant of the matrix ?", "choices": {"A": "-40", "B": "-6", "C": "40", "D": "104", "E": "160"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. A different whole number from 1 through 150 will be painted on each of the 150 parking spaces in a new parking lot. Each number will be painted using a minimum number of digits. For example, for space 15, 2 digits, 1 and 5, will be painted, and for the first 15 spaces, a total of 21 digits will be painted. In total, how many digits will be painted for all 150 parking spaces?", "choices": {"A": "150", "B": "287", "C": "337", "D": "339", "E": "342"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. How many seating arrangements are possible for 5 people to sit in the 5 seats of a car if 1 person sits in each seat and only 3 of the 5 people can sit in the driver's seat?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "12", "C": "24", "D": "72", "E": "120"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Let x be an odd integer greater than 1, and let b = x - 1.  The equation logb a = x is true. Which of the following phrases describes every value of a ?", "choices": {"A": "Odd only", "B": "Odd or 0 only", "C": "0 only", "D": "Odd and 0 only", "E": "Even and nonzero only"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. Quadrilateral ABCD in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane has these 4 vertices: A(0,6), B(-1,1), C(3,1), and D(3,6). Which of the following categories most precisely describes this quadrilateral?", "choices": {"A": "A parallelogram", "B": "A rhombus", "C": "An isosceles trapezoid", "D": "A quadrilateral that is not a trapezoid", "E": "A nonisosceles trapezoid"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. In the polynomial expansion of (x + y)5, what is the coefficient of the x2y3 term?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "4", "C": "6", "D": "10", "E": "15"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Meg has a bucket of plastic balls. Exactly 20% of these balls are yellow, and the rest are white. Some of the balls have a star on them. Exactly 6% of the balls are yellow and have a star on them. Meg will randomly draw 1 ball from the bucket. If the drawn ball is yellow, what is the probability that it will have a star on it?", "choices": {"A": "0.012", "B": "0.030", "C": "0.120", "D": "0.260", "E": "0.300"}, "correct": "E"}]}